<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OpenClaw</title>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.14</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:24:34 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>202602140</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.14</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.14</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: add poll sending via <code>openclaw message poll</code> (duration seconds, silent delivery, anonymity controls). (#16209) Thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>Slack/Discord: add <code>dmPolicy</code> + <code>allowFrom</code> config aliases for DM access control; legacy <code>dm.policy</code> + <code>dm.allowFrom</code> keys remain supported and <code>openclaw doctor --fix</code> can migrate them.</li>
<li>Discord: allow exec approval prompts to target channels or both DM+channel via <code>channels.discord.execApprovals.target</code>. (#16051) Thanks @leonnardo.</li>
<li>Sandbox: add <code>sandbox.browser.binds</code> to configure browser-container bind mounts separately from exec containers. (#16230) Thanks @seheepeak.</li>
<li>Discord: add debug logging for message routing decisions to improve <code>--debug</code> tracing. (#16202) Thanks @jayleekr.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>CLI/Plugins: ensure <code>openclaw message send</code> exits after successful delivery across plugin-backed channels so one-shot sends do not hang. (#16491) Thanks @yinghaosang.</li>
<li>CLI/Plugins: run registered plugin <code>gateway_stop</code> hooks before <code>openclaw message</code> exits (success and failure paths), so plugin-backed channels can clean up one-shot CLI resources. (#16580) Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: honor per-account <code>dmPolicy</code> overrides (account-level settings now take precedence over channel defaults for inbound DMs). (#10082) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Telegram: when <code>channels.telegram.commands.native</code> is <code>false</code>, exclude plugin commands from <code>setMyCommands</code> menu registration while keeping plugin slash handlers callable. (#15132) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>LINE: return 200 OK for Developers Console "Verify" requests (<code>{"events":[]}</code>) without <code>X-Line-Signature</code>, while still requiring signatures for real deliveries. (#16582) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Cron: deliver text-only output directly when <code>delivery.to</code> is set so cron recipients get full output instead of summaries. (#16360) Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Cron/Slack: preserve agent identity (name and icon) when cron jobs deliver outbound messages. (#16242) Thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>Media: accept <code>MEDIA:</code>-prefixed paths (lenient whitespace) when loading outbound media to prevent <code>ENOENT</code> for tool-returned local media paths. (#13107) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Agents: deliver tool result media (screenshots, images, audio) to channels regardless of verbose level. (#11735) Thanks @strelov1.</li>
<li>Agents/Image tool: allow workspace-local image paths by including the active workspace directory in local media allowlists, and trust sandbox-validated paths in image loaders to prevent false "not under an allowed directory" rejections. (#15541)</li>
<li>Agents/Image tool: propagate the effective workspace root into tool wiring so workspace-local image paths are accepted by default when running without an explicit <code>workspaceDir</code>. (#16722)</li>
<li>BlueBubbles: include sender identity in group chat envelopes and pass clean message text to the agent prompt, aligning with iMessage/Signal formatting. (#16210) Thanks @zerone0x.</li>
<li>CLI: fix lazy core command registration so top-level maintenance commands (<code>doctor</code>, <code>dashboard</code>, <code>reset</code>, <code>uninstall</code>) resolve correctly instead of exposing a non-functional <code>maintenance</code> placeholder command.</li>
<li>CLI/Dashboard: when <code>gateway.bind=lan</code>, generate localhost dashboard URLs to satisfy browser secure-context requirements while preserving non-LAN bind behavior. (#16434) Thanks @BinHPdev.</li>
<li>TUI/Gateway: resolve local gateway target URL from <code>gateway.bind</code> mode (tailnet/lan) instead of hardcoded localhost so <code>openclaw tui</code> connects when gateway is non-loopback. (#16299) Thanks @cortexuvula.</li>
<li>TUI: honor explicit <code>--session <key></code> in <code>openclaw tui</code> even when <code>session.scope</code> is <code>global</code>, so named sessions no longer collapse into shared global history. (#16575) Thanks @cinqu.</li>
<li>TUI: use available terminal width for session name display in searchable select lists. (#16238) Thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>TUI: refactor searchable select list description layout and add regression coverage for ANSI-highlight width bounds.</li>
<li>TUI: preserve in-flight streaming replies when a different run finalizes concurrently (avoid clearing active run or reloading history mid-stream). (#10704) Thanks @axschr73.</li>
<li>TUI: keep pre-tool streamed text visible when later tool-boundary deltas temporarily omit earlier text blocks. (#6958) Thanks @KrisKind75.</li>
<li>TUI: sanitize ANSI/control-heavy history text, redact binary-like lines, and split pathological long unbroken tokens before rendering to prevent startup crashes on binary attachment history. (#13007) Thanks @wilkinspoe.</li>
<li>TUI: harden render-time sanitizer for narrow terminals by chunking moderately long unbroken tokens and adding fast-path sanitization guards to reduce overhead on normal text. (#5355) Thanks @tingxueren.</li>
<li>TUI: render assistant body text in terminal default foreground (instead of fixed light ANSI color) so contrast remains readable on light themes such as Solarized Light. (#16750) Thanks @paymog.</li>
<li>TUI/Hooks: pass explicit reset reason (<code>new</code> vs <code>reset</code>) through <code>sessions.reset</code> and emit internal command hooks for gateway-triggered resets so <code>/new</code> hook workflows fire in TUI/webchat.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent <code>cron list</code>/<code>cron status</code> from silently skipping past-due recurring jobs by using maintenance recompute semantics. (#16156) Thanks @zerone0x.</li>
<li>Cron: repair missing/corrupt <code>nextRunAtMs</code> for the updated job without globally recomputing unrelated due jobs during <code>cron update</code>. (#15750)</li>
<li>Cron: skip missed-job replay on startup for jobs interrupted mid-run (stale <code>runningAtMs</code> markers), preventing restart loops for self-restarting jobs such as update tasks. (#16694) Thanks @sbmilburn.</li>
<li>Discord: prefer gateway guild id when logging inbound messages so cached-miss guilds do not appear as <code>guild=dm</code>. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Discord: treat empty per-guild <code>channels: {}</code> config maps as no channel allowlist (not deny-all), so <code>groupPolicy: "open"</code> guilds without explicit channel entries continue to receive messages. (#16714) Thanks @xqliu.</li>
<li>Models/CLI: guard <code>models status</code> string trimming paths to prevent crashes from malformed non-string config values. (#16395) Thanks @BinHPdev.</li>
<li>Gateway/Subagents: preserve queued announce items and summary state on delivery errors, retry failed announce drains, and avoid dropping unsent announcements on timeout/failure. (#16729) Thanks @Clawdette-Workspace.</li>
<li>Gateway/Sessions: abort active embedded runs and clear queued session work before <code>sessions.reset</code>, returning unavailable if the run does not stop in time. (#16576) Thanks @Grynn.</li>
<li>Sessions/Agents: harden transcript path resolution for mismatched agent context by preserving explicit store roots and adding safe absolute-path fallback to the correct agent sessions directory. (#16288) Thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>Agents: add a safety timeout around embedded <code>session.compact()</code> to ensure stalled compaction runs settle and release blocked session lanes. (#16331) Thanks @BinHPdev.</li>
<li>Agents: keep unresolved mutating tool failures visible until the same action retry succeeds, scope mutation-error surfacing to mutating calls (including <code>session_status</code> model changes), and dedupe duplicate failure warnings in outbound replies. (#16131) Thanks @Swader.</li>
<li>Agents/Process/Bootstrap: preserve unbounded <code>process log</code> offset-only pagination (default tail applies only when both <code>offset</code> and <code>limit</code> are omitted) and enforce strict <code>bootstrapTotalMaxChars</code> budgeting across injected bootstrap content (including markers), skipping additional injection when remaining budget is too small. (#16539) Thanks @CharlieGreenman.</li>
<li>Agents/Workspace: persist bootstrap onboarding state so partially initialized workspaces recover missing <code>BOOTSTRAP.md</code> once, while completed onboarding keeps BOOTSTRAP deleted even if runtime files are later recreated. Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Agents/Workspace: create <code>BOOTSTRAP.md</code> when core workspace files are seeded in partially initialized workspaces, while keeping BOOTSTRAP one-shot after onboarding deletion. (#16457) Thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>Agents: classify external timeout aborts during compaction the same as internal timeouts, preventing unnecessary auth-profile rotation and preserving compaction-timeout snapshot fallback behavior. (#9855) Thanks @mverrilli.</li>
<li>Agents: treat empty-stream provider failures (<code>request ended without sending any chunks</code>) as timeout-class failover signals, enabling auth-profile rotation/fallback and showing a friendly timeout message instead of raw provider errors. (#10210) Thanks @zenchantlive.</li>
<li>Agents: treat <code>read</code> tool <code>file_path</code> arguments as valid in tool-start diagnostics to avoid false “read tool called without path” warnings when alias parameters are used. (#16717) Thanks @Stache73.</li>
<li>Ollama/Agents: avoid forcing <code><final></code> tag enforcement for Ollama models, which could suppress all output as <code>(no output)</code>. (#16191) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>Plugins: suppress false duplicate plugin id warnings when the same extension is discovered via multiple paths (config/workspace/global vs bundled), while still warning on genuine duplicates. (#16222) Thanks @shadril238.</li>
<li>Skills: watch <code>SKILL.md</code> only when refreshing skills snapshot to avoid file-descriptor exhaustion in large data trees. (#11325) Thanks @household-bard.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: make <code>memory status</code> read-only by skipping QMD boot update/embed side effects for status-only manager checks.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: keep original QMD failures when builtin fallback initialization fails (for example missing embedding API keys), instead of replacing them with fallback init errors.</li>
<li>Memory/Builtin: keep <code>memory status</code> dirty reporting stable across invocations by deriving status-only manager dirty state from persisted index metadata instead of process-start defaults. (#10863) Thanks @BarryYangi.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: cap QMD command output buffering to prevent memory exhaustion from pathological <code>qmd</code> command output.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: parse qmd scope keys once per request to avoid repeated parsing in scope checks.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: query QMD index using exact docid matches before falling back to prefix lookup for better recall correctness and index efficiency.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: pass result limits to <code>search</code>/<code>vsearch</code> commands so QMD can cap results earlier.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: avoid reading full markdown files when a <code>from/lines</code> window is requested in QMD reads.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: skip rewriting unchanged session export markdown files during sync to reduce disk churn.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: make QMD result JSON parsing resilient to noisy command output by extracting the first JSON array from noisy <code>stdout</code>.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: treat prefixed <code>no results found</code> marker output as an empty result set in qmd JSON parsing. (#11302) Thanks @blazerui.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: avoid multi-collection <code>query</code> ranking corruption by running one <code>qmd query -c <collection></code> per managed collection and merging by best score (also used for <code>search</code>/<code>vsearch</code> fallback-to-query). (#16740) Thanks @volarian-vai.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: detect null-byte <code>ENOTDIR</code> update failures, rebuild managed collections once, and retry update to self-heal corrupted collection metadata. (#12919) Thanks @jorgejhms.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD/Security: add <code>rawKeyPrefix</code> support for QMD scope rules and preserve legacy <code>keyPrefix: "agent:..."</code> matching, preventing scoped deny bypass when operators match agent-prefixed session keys.</li>
<li>Memory/Builtin: narrow memory watcher targets to markdown globs and ignore dependency/venv directories to reduce file-descriptor pressure during memory sync startup. (#11721) Thanks @rex05ai.</li>
<li>Security/Memory-LanceDB: treat recalled memories as untrusted context (escape injected memory text + explicit non-instruction framing), skip likely prompt-injection payloads during auto-capture, and restrict auto-capture to user messages to reduce memory-poisoning risk. (#12524) Thanks @davidschmid24.</li>
<li>Security/Memory-LanceDB: require explicit <code>autoCapture: true</code> opt-in (default is now disabled) to prevent automatic PII capture unless operators intentionally enable it. (#12552) Thanks @fr33d3m0n.</li>
<li>Diagnostics/Memory: prune stale diagnostic session state entries and cap tracked session states to prevent unbounded in-memory growth on long-running gateways. (#5136) Thanks @coygeek and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Gateway/Memory: clean up <code>agentRunSeq</code> tracking on run completion/abort and enforce maintenance-time cap pruning to prevent unbounded sequence-map growth over long uptimes. (#6036) Thanks @coygeek and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Memory: bound <code>ABORT_MEMORY</code> growth by evicting oldest entries and deleting reset (<code>false</code>) flags so abort state tracking cannot grow unbounded over long uptimes. (#6629) Thanks @coygeek and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Slack/Memory: bound thread-starter cache growth with TTL + max-size pruning to prevent long-running Slack gateways from accumulating unbounded thread cache state. (#5258) Thanks @coygeek and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Outbound/Memory: bound directory cache growth with max-size eviction and proactive TTL pruning to prevent long-running gateways from accumulating unbounded directory entries. (#5140) Thanks @coygeek and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Skills/Memory: remove disconnected nodes from remote-skills cache to prevent stale node metadata from accumulating over long uptimes. (#6760) Thanks @coygeek.</li>
<li>Sandbox/Tools: make sandbox file tools bind-mount aware (including absolute container paths) and enforce read-only bind semantics for writes. (#16379) Thanks @tasaankaeris.</li>
<li>Media/Security: allow local media reads from OpenClaw state <code>workspace/</code> and <code>sandboxes/</code> roots by default so generated workspace media can be delivered without unsafe global path bypasses. (#15541) Thanks @lanceji.</li>
<li>Media/Security: harden local media allowlist bypasses by requiring an explicit <code>readFile</code> override when callers mark paths as validated, and reject filesystem-root <code>localRoots</code> entries. (#16739)</li>
<li>Discord/Security: harden voice message media loading (SSRF + allowed-local-root checks) so tool-supplied paths/URLs cannot be used to probe internal URLs or read arbitrary local files.</li>
<li>Security/BlueBubbles: require explicit <code>mediaLocalRoots</code> allowlists for local outbound media path reads to prevent local file disclosure. (#16322) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Security/BlueBubbles: reject ambiguous shared-path webhook routing when multiple webhook targets match the same guid/password.</li>
<li>Security/BlueBubbles: harden BlueBubbles webhook auth behind reverse proxies by only accepting passwordless webhooks for direct localhost loopback requests (forwarded/proxied requests now require a password). Thanks @simecek.</li>
<li>Feishu/Security: harden media URL fetching against SSRF and local file disclosure. (#16285) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Security/Zalo: reject ambiguous shared-path webhook routing when multiple webhook targets match the same secret.</li>
<li>Security/Nostr: require loopback source and block cross-origin profile mutation/import attempts. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Signal: harden signal-cli archive extraction during install to prevent path traversal outside the install root.</li>
<li>Security/Hooks: restrict hook transform modules to <code>~/.openclaw/hooks/transforms</code> (prevents path traversal/escape module loads via config). Config note: <code>hooks.transformsDir</code> must now be within that directory. Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Security/Hooks: ignore hook package manifest entries that point outside the package directory (prevents out-of-tree handler loads during hook discovery).</li>
<li>Security/Archive: enforce archive extraction entry/size limits to prevent resource exhaustion from high-expansion ZIP/TAR archives. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Media: reject oversized base64-backed input media before decoding to avoid large allocations. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Media: stream and bound URL-backed input media fetches to prevent memory exhaustion from oversized responses. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Skills: harden archive extraction for download-installed skills to prevent path traversal outside the target directory. Thanks @markmusson.</li>
<li>Security/Slack: compute command authorization for DM slash commands even when <code>dmPolicy=open</code>, preventing unauthorized users from running privileged commands via DM. Thanks @christos-eth.</li>
<li>Security/iMessage: keep DM pairing-store identities out of group allowlist authorization (prevents cross-context command authorization). Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Google Chat: deprecate <code>users/<email></code> allowlists (treat <code>users/...</code> as immutable user id only); keep raw email allowlists for usability. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Google Chat: reject ambiguous shared-path webhook routing when multiple webhook targets verify successfully (prevents cross-account policy-context misrouting). Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Telegram/Security: require numeric Telegram sender IDs for allowlist authorization (reject <code>@username</code> principals), auto-resolve <code>@username</code> to IDs in <code>openclaw doctor --fix</code> (when possible), and warn in <code>openclaw security audit</code> when legacy configs contain usernames. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Telegram/Security: reject Telegram webhook startup when <code>webhookSecret</code> is missing or empty (prevents unauthenticated webhook request forgery). Thanks @yueyueL.</li>
<li>Security/Windows: avoid shell invocation when spawning child processes to prevent cmd.exe metacharacter injection via untrusted CLI arguments (e.g. agent prompt text).</li>
<li>Telegram: set webhook callback timeout handling to <code>onTimeout: "return"</code> (10s) so long-running update processing no longer emits webhook 500s and retry storms. (#16763) Thanks @chansearrington.</li>
<li>Signal: preserve case-sensitive <code>group:</code> target IDs during normalization so mixed-case group IDs no longer fail with <code>Group not found</code>. (#16748) Thanks @repfigit.</li>
<li>Feishu/Security: harden media URL fetching against SSRF and local file disclosure. (#16285) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Security/Agents: scope CLI process cleanup to owned child PIDs to avoid killing unrelated processes on shared hosts. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Security/Agents: enforce workspace-root path bounds for <code>apply_patch</code> in non-sandbox mode to block traversal and symlink escape writes. Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Agents: enforce symlink-escape checks for <code>apply_patch</code> delete hunks under <code>workspaceOnly</code>, while still allowing deleting the symlink itself. Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Agents (macOS): prevent shell injection when writing Claude CLI keychain credentials. (#15924) Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>macOS: hard-limit unkeyed <code>openclaw://agent</code> deep links and ignore <code>deliver</code> / <code>to</code> / <code>channel</code> unless a valid unattended key is provided. Thanks @Cillian-Collins.</li>
<li>Scripts/Security: validate GitHub logins and avoid shell invocation in <code>scripts/update-clawtributors.ts</code> to prevent command injection via malicious commit records. Thanks @scanleale.</li>
<li>Security: fix Chutes manual OAuth login state validation by requiring the full redirect URL (reject code-only pastes) (thanks @aether-ai-agent).</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: harden tool-supplied <code>gatewayUrl</code> overrides by restricting them to loopback or the configured <code>gateway.remote.url</code>. Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: block <code>system.execApprovals.*</code> via <code>node.invoke</code> (use <code>exec.approvals.node.*</code> instead). Thanks @christos-eth.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: reject oversized base64 chat attachments before decoding to avoid large allocations. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: stop returning raw resolved config values in <code>skills.status</code> requirement checks (prevents operator.read clients from reading secrets). Thanks @simecek.</li>
<li>Security/Net: fix SSRF guard bypass via full-form IPv4-mapped IPv6 literals (blocks loopback/private/metadata access). Thanks @yueyueL.</li>
<li>Security/Browser: harden browser control file upload + download helpers to prevent path traversal / local file disclosure. Thanks @1seal.</li>
<li>Security/Browser: block cross-origin mutating requests to loopback browser control routes (CSRF hardening). Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Security/Node Host: enforce <code>system.run</code> rawCommand/argv consistency to prevent allowlist/approval bypass. Thanks @christos-eth.</li>
<li>Security/Exec approvals: prevent safeBins allowlist bypass via shell expansion (host exec allowlist mode only; not enabled by default). Thanks @christos-eth.</li>
<li>Security/Exec: harden PATH handling by disabling project-local <code>node_modules/.bin</code> bootstrapping by default, disallowing node-host <code>PATH</code> overrides, and spawning ACP servers via the current executable by default. Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Security/Tlon: harden Urbit URL fetching against SSRF by blocking private/internal hosts by default (opt-in: <code>channels.tlon.allowPrivateNetwork</code>). Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Voice Call (Telnyx): require webhook signature verification when receiving inbound events; configs without <code>telnyx.publicKey</code> are now rejected unless <code>skipSignatureVerification</code> is enabled. Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Voice Call: require valid Twilio webhook signatures even when ngrok free tier loopback compatibility mode is enabled. Thanks @p80n-sec.</li>
<li>Security/Discovery: stop treating Bonjour TXT records as authoritative routing (prefer resolved service endpoints) and prevent discovery from overriding stored TLS pins; autoconnect now requires a previously trusted gateway. Thanks @simecek.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.14/OpenClaw-2026.2.14.zip" length="22914034" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="lR3nuq46/akMIN8RFDpMkTE0VOVoDVG53Xts589LryMGEtUvJxRQDtHBXfx7ZvToTq6CFKG+L5Kq/4rUspMoAQ=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.15</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:04:34 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>202602150</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.15</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.15</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Discord: unlock rich interactive agent prompts with Components v2 (buttons, selects, modals, and attachment-backed file blocks) so for native interaction through Discord. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Discord: components v2 UI + embeds passthrough + exec approval UX refinements (CV2 containers, button layout, Discord-forwarding skip). Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Plugins: expose <code>llm_input</code> and <code>llm_output</code> hook payloads so extensions can observe prompt/input context and model output usage details. (#16724) Thanks @SecondThread.</li>
<li>Subagents: nested sub-agents (sub-sub-agents) with configurable depth. Set <code>agents.defaults.subagents.maxSpawnDepth: 2</code> to allow sub-agents to spawn their own children. Includes <code>maxChildrenPerAgent</code> limit (default 5), depth-aware tool policy, and proper announce chain routing. (#14447) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Slack/Discord/Telegram: add per-channel ack reaction overrides (account/channel-level) to support platform-specific emoji formats. (#17092) Thanks @zerone0x.</li>
<li>Cron/Gateway: add finished-run webhook delivery toggle (<code>notify</code>) and dedicated webhook auth token support (<code>cron.webhookToken</code>) for outbound cron webhook posts. (#14535) Thanks @advaitpaliwal.</li>
<li>Channels: deduplicate probe/token resolution base types across core + extensions while preserving per-channel error typing. (#16986) Thanks @iyoda and @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Security: replace deprecated SHA-1 sandbox configuration hashing with SHA-256 for deterministic sandbox cache identity and recreation checks. Thanks @kexinoh.</li>
<li>Security/Logging: redact Telegram bot tokens from error messages and uncaught stack traces to prevent accidental secret leakage into logs. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Sandbox/Security: block dangerous sandbox Docker config (bind mounts, host networking, unconfined seccomp/apparmor) to prevent container escape via config injection. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Sandbox: preserve array order in config hashing so order-sensitive Docker/browser settings trigger container recreation correctly. Thanks @kexinoh.</li>
<li>Gateway/Security: redact sensitive session/path details from <code>status</code> responses for non-admin clients; full details remain available to <code>operator.admin</code>. (#8590) Thanks @fr33d3m0n.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI: preserve requested operator scopes for Control UI bypass modes (<code>allowInsecureAuth</code> / <code>dangerouslyDisableDeviceAuth</code>) when device identity is unavailable, preventing false <code>missing scope</code> failures on authenticated LAN/HTTP operator sessions. (#17682) Thanks @leafbird.</li>
<li>LINE/Security: fail closed on webhook startup when channel token or channel secret is missing, and treat LINE accounts as configured only when both are present. (#17587) Thanks @davidahmann.</li>
<li>Skills/Security: restrict <code>download</code> installer <code>targetDir</code> to the per-skill tools directory to prevent arbitrary file writes. Thanks @Adam55A-code.</li>
<li>Skills/Linux: harden go installer fallback on apt-based systems by handling root/no-sudo environments safely, doing best-effort apt index refresh, and returning actionable errors instead of failing with spawn errors. (#17687) Thanks @mcrolly.</li>
<li>Web Fetch/Security: cap downloaded response body size before HTML parsing to prevent memory exhaustion from oversized or deeply nested pages. Thanks @xuemian168.</li>
<li>Config/Gateway: make sensitive-key whitelist suffix matching case-insensitive while preserving <code>passwordFile</code> path exemptions, preventing accidental redaction of non-secret config values like <code>maxTokens</code> and IRC password-file paths. (#16042) Thanks @akramcodez.</li>
<li>Dev tooling: harden git <code>pre-commit</code> hook against option injection from malicious filenames (for example <code>--force</code>), preventing accidental staging of ignored files. Thanks @mrthankyou.</li>
<li>Gateway/Agent: reject malformed <code>agent:</code>-prefixed session keys (for example, <code>agent:main</code>) in <code>agent</code> and <code>agent.identity.get</code> instead of silently resolving them to the default agent, preventing accidental cross-session routing. (#15707) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>Gateway/Chat: harden <code>chat.send</code> inbound message handling by rejecting null bytes, stripping unsafe control characters, and normalizing Unicode to NFC before dispatch. (#8593) Thanks @fr33d3m0n.</li>
<li>Gateway/Send: return an actionable error when <code>send</code> targets internal-only <code>webchat</code>, guiding callers to use <code>chat.send</code> or a deliverable channel. (#15703) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>Control UI: prevent stored XSS via assistant name/avatar by removing inline script injection, serving bootstrap config as JSON, and enforcing <code>script-src 'self'</code>. Thanks @Adam55A-code.</li>
<li>Agents/Security: sanitize workspace paths before embedding into LLM prompts (strip Unicode control/format chars) to prevent instruction injection via malicious directory names. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Agents/Sandbox: clarify system prompt path guidance so sandbox <code>bash/exec</code> uses container paths (for example <code>/workspace</code>) while file tools keep host-bridge mapping, avoiding first-attempt path misses from host-only absolute paths in sandbox command execution. (#17693) Thanks @app/juniordevbot.</li>
<li>Agents/Context: apply configured model <code>contextWindow</code> overrides after provider discovery so <code>lookupContextTokens()</code> honors operator config values (including discovery-failure paths). (#17404) Thanks @michaelbship and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents/Context: derive <code>lookupContextTokens()</code> from auth-available model metadata and keep the smallest discovered context window for duplicate model ids, preventing cross-provider cache collisions from overestimating session context limits. (#17586) Thanks @githabideri and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents/OpenAI: force <code>store=true</code> for direct OpenAI Responses/Codex runs to preserve multi-turn server-side conversation state, while leaving proxy/non-OpenAI endpoints unchanged. (#16803) Thanks @mark9232 and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Memory/FTS: make <code>buildFtsQuery</code> Unicode-aware so non-ASCII queries (including CJK) produce keyword tokens instead of falling back to vector-only search. (#17672) Thanks @KinGP5471.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Compaction: resolve <code>memory/YYYY-MM-DD.md</code> placeholders with timezone-aware runtime dates and append a <code>Current time:</code> line to memory-flush turns, preventing wrong-year memory filenames without making the system prompt time-variant. (#17603, #17633) Thanks @nicholaspapadam-wq and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents: return an explicit timeout error reply when an embedded run times out before producing any payloads, preventing silent dropped turns during slow cache-refresh transitions. (#16659) Thanks @liaosvcaf and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Group chats: always inject group chat context (name, participants, reply guidance) into the system prompt on every turn, not just the first. Prevents the model from losing awareness of which group it's in and incorrectly using the message tool to send to the same group. (#14447) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Browser/Agents: when browser control service is unavailable, return explicit non-retry guidance (instead of "try again") so models do not loop on repeated browser tool calls until timeout. (#17673) Thanks @austenstone.</li>
<li>Subagents: use child-run-based deterministic announce idempotency keys across direct and queued delivery paths (with legacy queued-item fallback) to prevent duplicate announce retries without collapsing distinct same-millisecond announces. (#17150) Thanks @widingmarcus-cyber.</li>
<li>Subagents/Models: preserve <code>agents.defaults.model.fallbacks</code> when subagent sessions carry a model override, so subagent runs fail over to configured fallback models instead of retrying only the overridden primary model.</li>
<li>Telegram: omit <code>message_thread_id</code> for DM sends/draft previews and keep forum-topic handling (<code>id=1</code> general omitted, non-general kept), preventing DM failures with <code>400 Bad Request: message thread not found</code>. (#10942) Thanks @garnetlyx.</li>
<li>Telegram: replace inbound <code><media:audio></code> placeholder with successful preflight voice transcript in message body context, preventing placeholder-only prompt bodies for mention-gated voice messages. (#16789) Thanks @Limitless2023.</li>
<li>Telegram: retry inbound media <code>getFile</code> calls (3 attempts with backoff) and gracefully fall back to placeholder-only processing when retries fail, preventing dropped voice/media messages on transient Telegram network errors. (#16154) Thanks @yinghaosang.</li>
<li>Telegram: finalize streaming preview replies in place instead of sending a second final message, preventing duplicate Telegram assistant outputs at stream completion. (#17218) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Discord: preserve channel session continuity when runtime payloads omit <code>message.channelId</code> by falling back to event/raw <code>channel_id</code> values for routing/session keys, so same-channel messages keep history across turns/restarts. Also align diagnostics so active Discord runs no longer appear as <code>sessionKey=unknown</code>. (#17622) Thanks @shakkernerd.</li>
<li>Discord: dedupe native skill commands by skill name in multi-agent setups to prevent duplicated slash commands with <code>_2</code> suffixes. (#17365) Thanks @seewhyme.</li>
<li>Discord: ensure role allowlist matching uses raw role IDs for message routing authorization. Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Web UI/Agents: hide <code>BOOTSTRAP.md</code> in the Agents Files list after onboarding is completed, avoiding confusing missing-file warnings for completed workspaces. (#17491) Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/WhatsApp/TUI/Web: when a final assistant message is <code>NO_REPLY</code> and a messaging tool send succeeded, mirror the delivered messaging-tool text into session-visible assistant output so TUI/Web no longer show <code>NO_REPLY</code> placeholders. (#7010) Thanks @Morrowind-Xie.</li>
<li>Cron: infer <code>payload.kind="agentTurn"</code> for model-only <code>cron.update</code> payload patches, so partial agent-turn updates do not fail validation when <code>kind</code> is omitted. (#15664) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>TUI: make searchable-select filtering and highlight rendering ANSI-aware so queries ignore hidden escape codes and no longer corrupt ANSI styling sequences during match highlighting. (#4519) Thanks @bee4come.</li>
<li>TUI/Windows: coalesce rapid single-line submit bursts in Git Bash into one multiline message as a fallback when bracketed paste is unavailable, preventing pasted multiline text from being split into multiple sends. (#4986) Thanks @adamkane.</li>
<li>TUI: suppress false <code>(no output)</code> placeholders for non-local empty final events during concurrent runs, preventing external-channel replies from showing empty assistant bubbles while a local run is still streaming. (#5782) Thanks @LagWizard and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>TUI: preserve copy-sensitive long tokens (URLs/paths/file-like identifiers) during wrapping and overflow sanitization so wrapped output no longer inserts spaces that corrupt copy/paste values. (#17515, #17466, #17505) Thanks @abe238, @trevorpan, and @JasonCry.</li>
<li>CLI/Build: make legacy daemon CLI compatibility shim generation tolerant of minimal tsdown daemon export sets, while preserving restart/register compatibility aliases and surfacing explicit errors for unavailable legacy daemon commands. Thanks @vignesh07.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.15/OpenClaw-2026.2.15.zip" length="22896513" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="MLGsd2NeHXFRH1Or0bFQnAjqfuuJDuhl1mvKFIqTQcRvwbeyvOyyLXrqSbmaOgJR3wBQBKLs6jYQ9dQ/3R8RCg=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.25</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 05:14:17 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>14883</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.25</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.25</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Android/Chat: improve streaming delivery handling and markdown rendering quality in the native Android chat UI, including better GitHub-flavored markdown behavior. (#26079) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Android/Startup perf: defer foreground-service startup, move WebView debugging init out of critical startup, and add startup macrobenchmark + low-noise perf CLI scripts for deterministic cold-start tracking. (#26659) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>UI/Chat compose: add mobile stacked layout for compose action buttons on small screens to improve send/session controls usability. (#11167) Thanks @junyiz.</li>
<li>Heartbeat/Config: replace heartbeat DM toggle with <code>agents.defaults.heartbeat.directPolicy</code> (<code>allow</code> | <code>block</code>; also supported per-agent via <code>agents.list[].heartbeat.directPolicy</code>) for clearer delivery semantics.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Security: clarify onboarding security notices that OpenClaw is personal-by-default (single trusted operator boundary) and shared/multi-user setups require explicit lock-down/hardening.</li>
<li>Branding/Docs + Apple surfaces: replace remaining <code>bot.molt</code> launchd label, bundle-id, logging subsystem, and command examples with <code>ai.openclaw</code> across docs, iOS app surfaces, helper scripts, and CLI test fixtures.</li>
<li>Agents/Config: remind agents to call <code>config.schema</code> before config edits or config-field questions to avoid guessing. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Dependencies: update workspace dependency pins and lockfile (Bedrock SDK <code>3.998.0</code>, <code>@mariozechner/pi-*</code> <code>0.55.1</code>, TypeScript native preview <code>7.0.0-dev.20260225.1</code>) while keeping <code>@buape/carbon</code> pinned.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Breaking</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>BREAKING:</strong> Heartbeat direct/DM delivery default is now <code>allow</code> again. To keep DM-blocked behavior from <code>2026.2.24</code>, set <code>agents.defaults.heartbeat.directPolicy: "block"</code> (or per-agent override).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Agents/Subagents delivery: refactor subagent completion announce dispatch into an explicit queue/direct/fallback state machine, recover outbound channel-plugin resolution in cold/stale plugin-registry states across announce/message/gateway send paths, finalize cleanup bookkeeping when announce flow rejects, and treat Telegram sends without <code>message_id</code> as delivery failures (instead of false-success <code>"unknown"</code> IDs). (#26867, #25961, #26803, #25069, #26741) Thanks @SmithLabsLLC and @docaohieu2808.</li>
<li>Telegram/Webhook: pre-initialize webhook bots, switch webhook processing to callback-mode JSON handling, and preserve full near-limit payload reads under delayed handlers to prevent webhook request hangs and dropped updates. (#26156)</li>
<li>Slack/Session threads: prevent oversized parent-session inheritance from silently bricking new thread sessions, surface embedded context-overflow empty-result failures to users, and add configurable <code>session.parentForkMaxTokens</code> (default <code>100000</code>, <code>0</code> disables). (#26912) Thanks @markshields-tl.</li>
<li>Cron/Message multi-account routing: honor explicit <code>delivery.accountId</code> for isolated cron delivery resolution, and when <code>message.send</code> omits <code>accountId</code>, fall back to the sending agent's bound channel account instead of defaulting to the global account. (#27015, #26975) Thanks @lbo728 and @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Gateway/Message media roots: thread <code>agentId</code> through gateway <code>send</code> RPC and prefer explicit <code>agentId</code> over session/default resolution so non-default agent workspace media sends no longer fail with <code>LocalMediaAccessError</code>; added regression coverage for agent precedence and blank-agent fallback. (#23249) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Followups/Routing: when explicit origin routing fails, allow same-channel fallback dispatch (while still blocking cross-channel fallback) so followup replies do not get dropped on transient origin-adapter failures. (#26109) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Cron/Announce duplicate guard: track attempted announce/direct delivery separately from confirmed <code>delivered</code>, and suppress fallback main-session cron summaries when delivery was already attempted to avoid duplicate end-user sends in uncertain-ack paths. (#27018)</li>
<li>LINE/Lifecycle: keep LINE <code>startAccount</code> pending until abort so webhook startup is no longer misread as immediate channel exit, preventing restart-loop storms on LINE provider boot. (#26528) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Discord/Gateway: capture and drain startup-time gateway <code>error</code> events before lifecycle listeners attach so early <code>Fatal Gateway error: 4014</code> closes surface as actionable intent guidance instead of uncaught gateway crashes. (#23832) Thanks @theotarr.</li>
<li>Discord/Inbound text: preserve embed <code>title</code> + <code>description</code> fallback text in message and forwarded snapshot parsing so embed titles are not silently dropped from agent input. (#26946) Thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Slack/Inbound media fallback: deliver file-only messages even when Slack media downloads fail by adding a filename placeholder fallback, capping fallback names to the shared media-file limit, and normalizing empty filenames to <code>file</code> so attachment-only messages are not silently dropped. (#25181) Thanks @justinhuangcode.</li>
<li>Telegram/Preview cleanup: keep finalized text previews when a later assistant message is media-only (for example mixed text plus voice turns) by skipping finalized preview archival at assistant-message boundaries, preventing cleanup from deleting already-visible final text messages. (#27042)</li>
<li>Telegram/Markdown spoilers: keep valid <code>||spoiler||</code> pairs while leaving unmatched trailing <code>||</code> delimiters as literal text, avoiding false all-or-nothing spoiler suppression. (#26105) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Slack/Allowlist channels: match channel IDs case-insensitively during channel allowlist resolution so lowercase config keys (for example <code>c0abc12345</code>) correctly match Slack runtime IDs (<code>C0ABC12345</code>) under <code>groupPolicy: "allowlist"</code>, preventing silent channel-event drops. (#26878) Thanks @lbo728.</li>
<li>Discord/Typing indicator: prevent stuck typing indicators by sealing channel typing keepalive callbacks after idle/cleanup and ensuring Discord dispatch always marks typing idle even if preview-stream cleanup fails. (#26295) Thanks @ngutman.</li>
<li>Channels/Typing indicator: guard typing keepalive start callbacks after idle/cleanup close so post-close ticks cannot re-trigger stale typing indicators. (#26325) Thanks @win4r.</li>
<li>Followups/Typing indicator: ensure followup turns mark dispatch idle on every exit path (including <code>NO_REPLY</code>, empty payloads, and agent errors) so typing keepalive cleanup always runs and channel typing indicators do not get stuck after queued/silent followups. (#26881) Thanks @codexGW.</li>
<li>Voice-call/TTS tools: hide the <code>tts</code> tool when the message provider is <code>voice</code>, preventing voice-call runs from selecting self-playback TTS and falling into silent no-output loops. (#27025)</li>
<li>Agents/Tools: normalize non-standard plugin tool results that omit <code>content</code> so embedded runs no longer crash with <code>Cannot read properties of undefined (reading 'filter')</code> after tool completion (including <code>tesseramemo_query</code>). (#27007)</li>
<li>Cron/Model overrides: when isolated <code>payload.model</code> is no longer allowlisted, fall back to default model selection instead of failing the job, while still returning explicit errors for invalid model strings. (#26717) Thanks @Youyou972.</li>
<li>Agents/Model fallback: keep explicit text + image fallback chains reachable even when <code>agents.defaults.models</code> allowlists are present, prefer explicit run <code>agentId</code> over session-key parsing for followup fallback override resolution (with session-key fallback), treat agent-level fallback overrides as configured in embedded runner preflight, and classify <code>model_cooldown</code> / <code>cooling down</code> errors as <code>rate_limit</code> so failover continues. (#11972, #24137, #17231)</li>
<li>Agents/Model fallback: keep same-provider fallback chains active when session model differs from configured primary, infer cooldown reason from provider profile state (instead of <code>disabledReason</code> only), keep no-profile fallback providers eligible (env/models.json paths), and only relax same-provider cooldown fallback attempts for <code>rate_limit</code>. (#23816) thanks @ramezgaberiel.</li>
<li>Agents/Model fallback: continue fallback traversal on unrecognized errors when candidates remain, while still throwing the original unknown error on the last candidate. (#26106) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Models/Auth probes: map permanent auth failover reasons (<code>auth_permanent</code>, for example revoked keys) into probe auth status instead of <code>unknown</code>, so <code>openclaw models status --probe</code> reports actionable auth failures. (#25754) thanks @rrenamed.</li>
<li>Hooks/Inbound metadata: include <code>guildId</code> and <code>channelName</code> in <code>message_received</code> metadata for both plugin and internal hook paths. (#26115) Thanks @davidrudduck.</li>
<li>Discord/Component auth: evaluate guild component interactions with command-gating authorizers so unauthorized users no longer get <code>CommandAuthorized: true</code> on modal/button events. (#26119) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway auth: require pairing for operator device-identity sessions authenticated with shared token auth so unpaired devices cannot self-assign operator scopes. Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway WebSocket auth: enforce origin checks for direct browser WebSocket clients beyond Control UI/Webchat, apply password-auth failure throttling to browser-origin loopback attempts (including localhost), and block silent auto-pairing for non-Control-UI browser clients to prevent cross-origin brute-force and session takeover chains. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @luz-oasis for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway trusted proxy: require <code>operator</code> role for the Control UI trusted-proxy pairing bypass so unpaired <code>node</code> sessions can no longer connect via <code>client.id=control-ui</code> and invoke node event methods. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/macOS beta onboarding: remove Anthropic OAuth sign-in and the legacy <code>oauth.json</code> onboarding path that exposed the PKCE verifier via OAuth <code>state</code>; this impacted the macOS beta onboarding path only. Anthropic subscription auth is now setup-token-only and will ship in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @zdi-disclosures for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Microsoft Teams file consent: bind <code>fileConsent/invoke</code> upload acceptance/decline to the originating conversation before consuming pending uploads, preventing cross-conversation pending-file upload or cancellation via leaked <code>uploadId</code> values; includes regression coverage for match/mismatch invoke handling. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: harden <code>agents.files</code> path handling to block out-of-workspace symlink targets for <code>agents.files.get</code>/<code>agents.files.set</code>, keep in-workspace symlink targets supported, and add gateway regression coverage for both blocked escapes and allowed in-workspace symlinks. Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Workspace FS: reject hardlinked workspace file aliases in <code>tools.fs.workspaceOnly</code> and <code>tools.exec.applyPatch.workspaceOnly</code> boundary checks (including sandbox mount-root guards) to prevent out-of-workspace read/write via in-workspace hardlink paths. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Browser temp paths: harden trace/download output-path handling against symlink-root and symlink-parent escapes with realpath-based write-path checks plus secure fallback tmp-dir validation that fails closed on unsafe fallback links. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Browser uploads: revalidate upload paths at use-time in Playwright file-chooser and direct-input flows so missing/rebound paths are rejected before <code>setFiles</code>, with regression coverage for strict missing-path handling.</li>
<li>Security/Exec approvals: bind <code>system.run</code> approval matching to exact argv identity and preserve argv whitespace in rendered command text, preventing trailing-space executable path swaps from reusing a mismatched approval. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Exec approvals: harden approval-bound <code>system.run</code> execution on node hosts by rejecting symlink <code>cwd</code> paths and canonicalizing path-like executable argv before spawn, blocking mutable-cwd symlink retarget chains between approval and execution. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Signal: enforce DM/group authorization before reaction-only notification enqueue so unauthorized senders can no longer inject Signal reaction system events under <code>dmPolicy</code>/<code>groupPolicy</code>; reaction notifications now require channel access checks first. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Discord reactions: enforce DM policy/allowlist authorization before reaction-event system enqueue in direct messages; Discord reaction handling now also honors DM/group-DM enablement and guild <code>groupPolicy</code> channel gating to keep reaction ingress aligned with normal message preflight. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Slack reactions + pins: gate <code>reaction_*</code> and <code>pin_*</code> system-event enqueue through shared sender authorization so DM <code>dmPolicy</code>/<code>allowFrom</code> and channel <code>users</code> allowlists are enforced consistently for non-message ingress, with regression coverage for denied/allowed sender paths. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Telegram reactions: enforce <code>dmPolicy</code>/<code>allowFrom</code> and group allowlist authorization on <code>message_reaction</code> events before enqueueing reaction system events, preventing unauthorized reaction-triggered input in DMs and groups; ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Slack interactions: enforce channel/DM authorization and modal actor binding (<code>private_metadata.userId</code>) before enqueueing <code>block_action</code>/<code>view_submission</code>/<code>view_closed</code> system events, with regression coverage for unauthorized senders and missing/mismatched actor metadata. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Nextcloud Talk: drop replayed signed webhook events with persistent per-account replay dedupe across restarts, and reject unexpected webhook backend origins when account base URL is configured. Thanks @aristorechina for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Nextcloud Talk: reject unsigned webhook traffic before full body reads, reducing unauthenticated request-body exposure, with auth-order regression coverage. (#26118) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/Nextcloud Talk: stop treating DM pairing-store entries as group allowlist senders, so group authorization remains bounded to configured group allowlists. (#26116) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/LINE: cap unsigned webhook body reads before auth/signature handling to bound unauthenticated body processing. (#26095) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/IRC: keep pairing-store approvals DM-only and out of IRC group allowlist authorization, with policy regression tests for allowlist resolution. (#26112) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/Microsoft Teams: isolate group allowlist and command authorization from DM pairing-store entries to prevent cross-context authorization bleed. (#26111) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Security/SSRF guard: classify IPv6 multicast literals (<code>ff00::/8</code>) as blocked/private-internal targets in shared SSRF IP checks, preventing multicast literals from bypassing URL-host preflight and DNS answer validation. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.25</code>). Thanks @zpbrent for reporting.</li>
<li>Tests/Low-memory stability: disable Vitest <code>vmForks</code> by default on low-memory local hosts (<code><64 GiB</code>), keep low-profile extension lane parallelism at 4 workers, and align cron isolated-agent tests with <code>setSessionRuntimeModel</code> usage to avoid deterministic suite failures. (#26324) Thanks @ngutman.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.25/OpenClaw-2026.2.25.zip" length="23078398" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="PJjvRhivhybV5bYr8u1C9Dyw4h8yePGwG8SFsr4QRqMSBYMEedraPJO3KNbkoChjclYUYf3oGcC4daNZnFvgBA=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>